[
    {
        "question": "Your application is hosted by a provider on yourapp.provider.com. You would like to have your users access your application using www.your-domain.com, which you own and manage under Route 53. How can you achieve this?\n \nA.) Create an Alias Record \n B.) Create an A Record \n C.) Create a CNAME Record \n D.) Create a PTR Record", 
        "answer": "C.) Create a CNAME Record\nDomain: Design Cost-Optimized Architectures\nA CNAME record maps DNS queries for the name of the current record, such as abc.example.com, to another domain name, such as yourapp.provider.com. When you create a CNAME record, you specify the domain name that you want to map to another domain name.\nNOTE: DNS Protocol does not allow CNAME records for top node of a dns namespace (zone apex). For example, if you register the DNS name example.com, the zone apex is example.com therefore you cannot create a CNAME record, but you can create one for www.example.com."
    },
    {
        "question":"The engineering team at an e-commerce company wants to migrate from Amazon Simple Queue Service Standard queues to FIFO queues. Which of the following statements are true regarding this migration? (Select THREE.)\n \nA.) Make sure that the throughput for the target FIFO queue does not exceed 3000 messages per second.\n B.) Convert the existing standard queue into a FIFO queue.\nC.) Make sure that the throughput for the target FIFO queue does not exceed 300 messages per second.\nD.) Make sure that the name of the FIFO queue is the same as the standard.\nE.) Delete the existing standard queue and recreate it as a FIFO queue.\nF.) Make sure that the name of the FIFO queue ends with .fifo.",
        "answer":"A.) Make sure that the throughput for the target FIFO queue does not exceed 3000 messages per second.\nD.) Delete the existing standard queue and recreate it as a FIFO queue.\nF.) Make sure that the name of the FIFO queue ends with .fifo.\nDomain: Design Resilient Architectures\nFIFO (First-In-First-Out) queues are designed to enhance messaging between applications when the order of operations and events is critical, or where duplicates can't be tolerated. FIFO queues support up to 300 messages per second without batching, or up to 3,000 messages per second with batching. FIFO queue names must end with the .fifo suffix. Standard queues cannot be converted to FIFO queues; you must create a new FIFO queue and migrate your messages accordingly."
    },
    {
        "question":"A data analytics company manages an application that stores user data in a DynamoDB Table. The development team has observed that once in a while, the application writes corrupted data in the table. As soon as the issue is detected, the team needs to remove the corrupted data at the earliest. What do you recommend?\n\n A.) Configure the Amazone DynamoDB table as a global table and point the application to use the table from another AWS region that has no corrupted data.\nB.) Use DynamoDB Streams to restore the table to the state before corrupted data was written.\n C.) Use DynamoDB point in time recovery to restore the table.\n D.) Use Amazon DynamoDB on demand backup to restore the table.",
        "answer":"C.) Use DynamoDB point in time recovery to restore the table.\nDomain: Design Resilient Architectures.\nPoint in time recovery in dynamoDB backs up your table data automatically with per second granularity so that you can restore to any given second in the preceding 35 days. On-Demand backups cannot be created pre-emptively to handle data corruption issues that happen occassionally."
    },
    {
        "question":"A company has its application servers in the public subnet that connect to the db instances in the private subnet. For regular maintenance, the db instances need patch fixes that need to be downloaded from the internet.\nConsidering the company uses only IPv4 addressing and is looking for a managed service which of the following would you suggest as an optimal solution.\n\nA.) Configure an Egress-only internet gateway for the resources in the private subnet.\nB.) Configure a NAT instance in the public subnet of the VPC.\nC.) Configure the internet gateway of the vpc to be accessible to the private subnet resources by changing the route tables.\nD.) Configure a NAT Gateway in the public subnet."
        ,"answer":"D.) Configrue a NAT gateway in the public subnet.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures.\nNAT gateways enable instances in a private subnet to connect to the internet or other AWS services, but prevent the internet from initiating a connection with those instances. NAT Gateways reside in the public subnet, and must have an elastic IP address associated.\nInternet Gateways cannot be used directly with a private subnet. A NAT instance or gateway is required to use an internet gateway."
    },
    {
        "question":"The engineering team at a social media company wants to use CloudWatch alarms to automatically recover EC2 instances if they become impaired. The team has hired you as an S.A to provide subject matter expertise.\nAs an S.A, which of the following would you identify as correct regarding this automatic recovery process? (Select TWO).\n\nA.) If your instance has a public IPv4 address, it retains the same public IPv4 address after recovery.\nB.) If your instance has a public IPv4, it does not retain the public IPv4 after recovery.\nC.) A recovered instance is identical to the original instance, including the instance ID, private IP addresses, Elastic IP addresses, and all instance metadata.\nD.) During instance recovery, the instance is migrated during an instance reboot, and any data that is in memory is retained.\nE.) Terminated EC2 Instances can be recovered if they are configured at the launch of the instance.",
        "answer": "A.) If your instance has a public IPv4 address, it retains the same public IPv4 address after recovery.\nC.) A recovered instance is identical to the original instance, including the instance ID, private IP addresses, Elastic IP addresses, and all instance metadata.\nDomain: Design Resilient Architectures.\nWhen an instance is recovered, it is migrated to a new host computer. The instance retains its instance ID, private IP addresses, Elastic IP addresses, and all instance metadata. If the instance has a public IPv4 address, it also retains that address after recovery. Data that is in memory is lost during recovery because the instance is stopped and started on a new host."
    },
    {
        "question":"An AWS Organization s using Service Control Policies for central control over the max available permissions for all accounts in the organization. This allows the organization to ensure all accounts stay within the organization's access control guidelines.\nWhich of the given scenarios are correct regarding the permissions described below? (Select THREE).\n\nA.) Service control policy affects service linked roles.\nB.) If a user or role has an IAM permission policy that grants access to an action that is either not allowed or explicitly denied by the applicable service control policy, the user or role can still perform that action.\nC.) Service control policy does not affect service-linked roles.\nD.) If a user or role has an IAM permission policy that grants access to an action that is either not allowed or explicitly denied by the applicable service control policy, the user or role cant perform that action.\nE.) Service control policies affect all users and roles in the members accounts excluding the root user of the member accounts.\nF.) Service control policy affects all users and roles in the member accounts, including the root user of the member accounts.",
        "answer":"B.) SCP does not affect service-linked roles.\nC.) If a user or role has an IAM permission policy that grants access to an action that is either not allowed or explicitly denied by the applicable service control policy, the user or role can't perform that action.\nF.) Service Control Policy affects all users and roles in the member accounts, including the root user of the member accounts.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures.\nSCP offers central control over the max available permissions for all accounts in your org, ensuring accounts stay within access control policies. In SCP, you can restrict AWS services, resources, and individual API actions the user and roles in each member account can access. \nNote: the following effects on permissions vis-a-vis service control policy: If a user or role has an IAM permission policy that grants access to an action that is not allowed or explicitly denied by the SCP, the user or role can perform that action."
    },
    {
        "question":"An e-commerce company runs its web app on EC2 instance in an ASG and it is configured to handle consumer orders in an SQS queue for downstream processing. The DevOps team has observed that the performance of the application goes down in case of a sudden spike in orders received. As a solutions architect, which of the following solutions would you recommend to address this use-case?\nA.) Use a target tracking scaling policy based on a custom Amazon SQS queue metric.\nB.) Use a step scaling policy based on a custom SQS queue metric.\n C.) Use a scheduled scaling policy based on an SQS metric. \nD.) Use a simple scaling policy based on a SQS metric.",
        "answer":"A.) Use a target tracking policy.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures.\nTarget Scaling is dynamic and can adjust to the demand curve of your app more effectively than step or simple."
    },
    {
        "question":"A developer has configured inbound traffic for the relevant ports in both the security groups of the EC2 instance as well as the Network ACL of the subnet for the EC2. The developer, however, is unable to connect to the service running on the EC2. How can you fix this issue?\n\nA.) IAM role defined in the Security Group is different from the IAM Role that is given access in the Network ACLs.\nB.) Rules associated with the Network ACLs should never be modified from command line. An attempt to modify rules from command line blocks the rule and results in an erratic behavior.\nC.) Security Groups are stateful, so allowing inbound traffic to necessary ports enables the connection. Network ACLs are stateless, so you must allow both inbound and outbound traffic.D.) Network ACLs are stateful, so allowing inbound traffic to necesary ports enables the connection. Security Groups are stateless, so you must allow both inbound and outbound traffic.",
        "answer":"C.) Security Groups are stateful, so allowing inbound traffic to necessary ports enables the connection. Network ACLs are stateless, so you must allow both inbound and outbound traffic.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures."
    },
    {
        "question":"The db backend for a retail company website is hosted on RDS for MySQL having a primary instance and 3 read replicas to support read scalability. The company has mandated that the read replicas should lag no more than 1 second behind the primary instance to provide the best possible user experience. The read replicas are falling further behind during high traffic, resulting in poor user experience. How would you reduce the replication lag as much as possible with minimal changes to the app code or the effort required to manage the underlying resources?\n\nA.) Set up a db migration from RDS MySql to DynamoDb. Provision a large number of read capacity units to support the required throughput and enable Auto Scaling.\nB.) Set up Elastic Cache for Redis Cluster in front of the db. Update website to check the chache before querying the read replicas.\nC.)Set up a db migration to Aurora MySql. Swap out the MySql read replicas with Aurora Replicas. Configure Aurora Auto Scaling.\nD.) Host the MySql primary db on a memory optimized EC2 instance. Spin up additional compute optimized EC2 instance to host read replicas.",
        "answer":"C.)Migrate to Aurora and swap the mysql read replicas with aurora replicas. Configure aurora auto scaling.\nDomain: Design High Performing Architectures.\n Aurora is a distributed, fault tolerant, and self healing storage system that is decoupled from compute resources and auto scales up to 128TiB per db instance. It delivers high performance and availability with up to 15 low-latency read replicas, point in time recovery, continuous backup to s3, and replication across 3 AZs. The replica lag times are in the 10s of milliseconds. \n Note: when talking about minimizing db read replica lag -- Aurora is a good option."
    },
    {
        "question":"The DevOps team at a multi-national company is helping its subsidiaries standardize EC2 instances by using the same AMI. Some of these subsidiaries are in the same region but use different AWS accounts, whereas others are in different AWS regions but use the same AWS account as the parent company. Which of the following are correct regarding AMIs? (Select Three)\n\nA.)You can share an AMI with another AWS account.\nB.) You can not copy an AMI across Regions.\nC.) You can copy an AMI across regions.\nD.) You cannot share an AMI with another Account.\ne.) Copying an AMI backed by an encrypted snapshot cannot result in an unencrypted target snapshot.",
        "answer": "A.) You can share an AMI with another AWS account.\nC.) You can copy an AMI across regions.\nE.) Copying an AMI backed by an encrypted snapshot cannot result in an unencrypted target snapshot.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures.\nYou can share an AMI with specific AWS accounts or make it public. You can copy an AMI from one region to another. When you copy an AMI that is backed by an encrypted snapshot, the target snapshot is also encrypted. You cannot copy an encrypted snapshot and have the target snapshot be unencrypted.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures.\nFor more information, go to https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/CopyingAMIs.html"
    },
    {
        "question":"The DevOps team at an IT company is provisioning a two-tier application in a VPC with a public and private subnet. The team wants to use either a NAT instance or a NAT gateway in the public subnet to enable instances in the private subnet to initiate outbound IPv4 traffic to the internet but needs some technical assistance in terms of the configuration options available for the NAT instance and gateway. As an SA, choose the three correct options.\n\nA.) Security Groups can be associated with a NAT instance.\nB.) NAT Gateways supports port forwarding.\nC.) NAT Gateway can be used as a bastion server.\nD.) Security groups can be associated with a NAT Gateway.\nE.) NAT instance supports port forwarding.\nF.) NAT Instance can be used as a bastion server.",
        "Answer":"A.) Security Groups can be associated with a NAT instance.\nE.) NAT instance supports port forwarding.\nF.) NAT Instance can be used as a bastion server.\nDomain: Design Secure Architectures.\nA NAT instance is an EC2 instance configured to forward traffic to the internet. You can associate security groups with a NAT instance, and you can configure it to support port forwarding. Additionally, since it's an EC2 instance, it can also be used as a bastion server. On the other hand, a NAT Gateway is a managed service that does not support security groups or port forwarding and cannot be used as a bastion server. Security groups can be associated with resources behind the NAT gateway to control inbound and outbound traffic."
    },
    {
        "question":"A company wants to move the windows file server clusters out of their datacenters. They are looking for cloud file storage offerings that provide full Windows Capability. Identify the AWS storage services that provide highly reliable file storage that is accessible over the industry standard server block protocol compatible with Windows systems. (Select Two)\n\nA.) File Gateway Configuration of AWS Storage Gateway\nB.) Amazon EBS\nC.) EFS \nD.) Amazon FSx for Windows File Server\nE.) Amazon S3",
        "answer":"A.) File Gateway Configuration of AWS Storage Gateway\nD.) Amazon FSx for Windows File Server\nDomain: Design Resilient Architectures.\nStorage gateway enables you to store and retrieve objects in S3 using file protocols such as Network File System (NFS) and Server Message Block (SMB)."
    },
    {
        "question":"A company hosts windows based apps on its on prem data center. The company is looking at moving the business to the cloud. The solution should offer shared storage space that multiple applications can access without replication. Also the solution should integrate with the company's self managed Active Directory. Which solution addresses the requirements with minimal integration effort.\n\nA.) Use File Gateway of AWS Storage Gateway to create a hybrid storage.\nB.) Use FSx for Windows File Server as a shared storage solution.\nC.) Use FSx Lustre.\nD.) Use EFS."
        ,"answer":"B.) FSx for Windows File Server.\nDomain: Design Resilient Architectures.\nAmazon FSx for Windows File Server provides a fully managed native Microsoft Windows file system so you can easily move your Windows-based applications that require file storage to AWS. It is built on Windows Server and supports SMB protocol, Windows NTFS, and Active Directory (AD) integration."
    }
]